UNITE HERE Legal Department ACTWU Files 6200/002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE Legal Department ACTWU Files
1969-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE
Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union (ACTWU)
6200/002
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records.
6273082
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, March 03, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 03, 2016
Biographical / Historical
UNITE HERE is a labor union in the United States and Canada, that was formed in 2004 by the merger of the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE) and Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE). The membership is made up mainly of workers in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries. In 2005, UNITE HERE left the AFL-CIO and joined the Change to Win Federation along with other unions including the Teamsters, SEIU and the UFCW. In may 2009, Bruce Raynor, president, left UNITE HERE, taking with hiim several local unions and between 105,000 and 150,000 members. They formed Workers United. September 17, 2009, UNITE HERE announced that it would re-join the AFL-CIO.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6200: UNITE HERE Records
Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States; Textile workers--Labor unions--United States.; Collective bargaining--Textile industry-- United States.; Collective bargaining--Clothing industry--United States.; UNITE HERE (Organization); Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Textile Workers Union of America; UNITE HERE (Organization) Legal Dept.
6273082
- Agreement and Plan of Merger and Consolidation: ACWA-TWUA., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Exhibits E - M.
- Agreement and Plan of Merger and Consolidation: ACWA-TWUA. [copy 2], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Letters and Certificates.
- Agreement and Plan of Merger and Consolidation: ACWA-TWUA. Agreement - [copy 2], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Exhibits A - D.
- Agreement and Plan of Merger and Consolidation: ACWA-TWUA. [copy 2], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agreement and Plan of Merger and Consolidation: ACWA-TWUA. [copy 3], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agreement and Plan of Merger and Consolidation: ACWA-TWUA. Agreement - [copy 3], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Agreement and Plan of Merger and Consolidation: ACWA-TWUA. [copy 3], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Agreement and Plan of Merger: ACTWU - United Shoe Workers of America. [2 copies], 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Agreement and Plan of Merger: ACTWU - Cap and Millinery Workers Union. [2 copies], 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Agreement and Declaration of Trust, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  The Amalgamated Cotton Garment and Allied Industries Fund.
- ACWA: National Agreement., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  2 copies
- ACWA: Supplemental Agreement., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- ACTWU: National Agreement., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- ACTWU: National Agreement., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- ACTWU: National Agreement., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- ACTWU: National Agreement., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- ACTWU: National Agreement., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- ACTWU: National Agreement., 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)